Packer.
Packer﻿
Yes, Mr Vaughn?
什么事, Vaughn 先生
Packer, those two uninvited guests
we had this morning,
Packer, 今天早上那两位不速之客
- I assume they were photographed?
- Yes, sir.
- 我估计给他们拍照了吧？  - 是的, 先生
Have some prints taken and sent up to me.
打印几份, 送到我这里来
- Well, what do we do now, Doctor?
- Accept the situation, Jamie.
- 怎样, 我们现在怎么做, 博士？  - 接受现状, Jamie
Nothing else we can do.
我们没什么可做的
You're still worried about
your two friends, aren't you? Why?
你还是担心你的两个朋友, 是不？为什么？
Oh, I don't know.
噢, 我不知道
I've just got this feeling
that something's happened to them.
我只是有这种感觉, 有事发生在他们身上了
- Why on earth should it have?
- No reason at all, really.
- 到底为什么会有事呢？  - 完全没理由, 真的
It's not a logical conclusion, just intuition.
不是一个有逻辑的结论, 只是直觉
Well, I'll tell you what we'll do, then.
好, 那我告诉你我们该怎么做
- We'll go right out after them, okay?
- Oh, yes, please.
- 我们这就出去找他们, ＯＫ？  - 哦, 好
But we'd better leave a note for them,
但我们最好给他们留个信息
just in case they come back when we're not here.
以免他们回来时我们又不在
Would you mind telling us what all this is about?
你能否告诉我们, 这都是怎么一回事吗？
- You'll find out, sir.
- Sir?
- 你会明白的, 先生  - 先生?
- All right, Benton, thank you.  - Sir.
- 没事了, Benton, 谢谢你  - 是
- NAAFI break, sir?  - Very well.
- NAAFI 有间歇了(?)， 长官？  - 很好
(NAAFI: 英国陆海空三军合作所)
How nice to see you again, Doctor.
很高兴再见到你, 博士
It's Colonel Lethbridge-Stewart!
是 Lethbridge-Stewart 上校！
Ah, Brigadier now. I've gone up in the world.
啊, 现在是准将了．我在这里升职了
Of course, the Yetis. We met you in the...
当然了, 雪怪那回, 我们跟你碰过面, 在...
That's right, McCrimmon, in the Underground.
对的, McCrimmon, 在地下
Must be four years ago now.
肯定是四年以前了
That long. It only seems like
a couple of weeks ago, doesn't it?
那么久？感觉好像才几个星期而已, 是吧？
I've told you over and over again, Jamie.
Time is relative.
我跟你说了一遍又一遍, Jamie．时间是相对的
Are you still making a nonsense of it, Doctor,
in your... What was it called?
你还在讲这些笑话吗, 博士, 在你的...它是叫什么来着？
- Tardis?  - Yes, we're still travelling. Yes.
- TARDIS?  - 是的, 我们还在旅行, 是的
Yes, Mr Travers told me all about it.
是, Travers 先生都说给我听了
It's, um... Well, it's...
那是个, 嗯...怎么说, 是个...
To say the least, an unbelievable machine.
简单说吧, 一台不可思议的机器
DOCTOR: Any more unbelievable than the Yetis, hmm?
比雪怪还不可思议吗, 嗯？
No, true. I'm not quite
so much of a sceptic as I was
没有, 的确．我不再像以前那样怀疑这些
- since that little escapade.
- But what's all this,
- 就自打上次灵异事件之后  - 但这些都是什么意思？
and why all the cloak and dagger stuff
to bring us here?
为什么这些带着斗篷和剑的家伙把我们带到这里来?
Yes, I'm sorry about that, but my chaps have to
be a bit melodramatic in their methods.
是的, 对此我表示抱歉．但我的人必须在执行力上强一些
But I'll explain. Oh, do sit down.
但我会解释的．哦, 请坐下吧
- Thank you.  - How nice.
- 谢谢你  - 很好
(WHIRRING)
Has the information been considered?
这个信息已经考虑过了吗？
COMMUNICATOR: The images of the two humans
这两个人的图像
have been analysed and registered.
已经被分析和记录了
They are known and are hostile.
他们是已知的敌人
Hostile? How can that be?
敌人？怎么可能呢？
Have you been on Earth before?
你们以前到过地球吗？
No, they have been recognised
没有, 他们已经被认出来了
They are dangerous and must be destroyed.
他们很危险, 必须被消灭
Yes, well, since the Yeti do,
是的, 自从雪怪事件以后
I've been in charge of an independent intelligence group
我就负责了一个独立的情报组
that we call UNIT, that's
United Nations Intelligence Taskforce.
我们叫它 UNIT, 也就是＂联合国情报行动组＂
You mean you're like a... A world secret police?
你是说, 你就像一个...秘密的世界警察？
Not quite. We don't actually arrest people,
we just investigate them.
不大对．我们实际上并不逮捕人, 我们只是调查他们
What about us? I mean, you arrested us.
那我们呢？我是说, 你逮捕了我们
Not really.
并不是
You see, my men were keeping a watch on
the International Electromatic Headquarters
你看, 我的人一直在监视国际电气自动话公司的总部
when you two showed up.
这时候你们俩出现了
I've been keeping a check
on everyone going in that building.
我一直在核查进入那栋大楼的每一个人
Your photographs were transmitted
to this Headquarters and I recognised you.
你们的照片传到总部, 我认出了你们
Well, what's so odd about
people going into the building?
那, 进入那栋大楼的有什么奇怪的？
Oh, nothing odd about them going in.
噢, 进入的人倒没有什么奇怪
The problem is some of them haven't come out.
问题在于有些人一直没有出来
BRIGADIER: This is Gordon Jones,
lecturer in physics, Churchill College, Cambridge.
这位是 Gordon Jones, 物理学讲师, 剑桥丘吉尔学院
Next one's a chap I knew at Sandhurst,
old Billy Rutlidge.
下一个是我在 Sandhurst 就认识的, 老 Billy Rutlidge
(Sandhurst 是英国陆军官校所在地)
He's got himself a very cushy number
at the Ministry of Defence.
他给自己在国防部找了一个待遇很不错的岗位
And all these people went into the building,
the IE building, and didn't come out.
这些人都走进了那栋大楼, IE 的大楼, 然后没有出来
No, no, most of them came out again,
不, 不, 他们中大多数人又出来了
but there was something definitely odd
about them when they did.
但他们出来的时候绝对都有些古怪
Odd?
古怪？
Ah, yes, Miss Watkins.
啊, 是, Watkins 小姐
You're concerned about your uncle, aren't you?
你在担心你的叔叔, 是吗？
I'd like to know where he is, yes.
是, 我想知道他在那里
He's perfectly well, I assure you,
although a little, uh...
他非常好, 我可以向你保证, 虽然有一点...
uncooperative at the moment.
目前来说不太合作
Your visit here is most opportune.
你们来的时机相当好
I think that you can be very useful to me.
我觉得你会对我非常有用
Me? But... But how?
我？但是...怎么会？
Your uncle needs to be ''persuaded''
to continue his work for me.
你叔叔需要一点＂说服＂工作, 才能继续为我服务
But I can't do anything about that.
但我对此做不了什么
No.
不能
But I can. Now...
但我可以．现在...
Packer, I'd like you to take care
of these two young ladies, please.
Packer, 我想请你照顾一下这两位年轻的女士
Take them!
把她们带走！
(GIRLS PROTESTING)
Um, Brigadier, tell me more about this
唔, 准将, 多告诉我一些信息
International Electromatics setup.
关于这个国际电气自动化公司的情况
Well, there isn't much to tell.
这个, 没有太多可说的
The head of the group
is a man named Tobias Vaughn.
这个组织的头儿是一个叫做 Tobias Vaughn 的人
Oh, yes, we've met him. A nice man.
哦, 是的, 我已经见过他了．一个不错的人
- He gave me this.  - Jamie.
- 他给了我们这个  - Jamie﻿
- Oh, yes, that's just the small stuff.
- Put it away.
- 噢, 是的, 就是这种小东西  - 把它收起来
They control practically
all of the major computer lines.
他们实际上控制了几乎所有主要的电脑生产线
They made their real breakthrough
in micromonolithic circuit designing.
他们在微型单晶片电路设计方面还真有些突破
Undercutting practically everyone else
on the market.
事实上把市场上的其他对手都挤出去了
But what's your interest in this?
但你们为什么对这个感兴趣？
Well, I knew a little about Vaughn
before his sudden success.
在 Vaughn 突然成功之前, 我对它知之甚少
I put out a routine check on him and
we came up with one or two things of interest.
我对他进行了例行检查, 发现了一两项感兴趣的事情
Like the disappearance of Professor Watkins.
比如 Watkins 教授的失踪
- Yes.  - Ah, see.
- 是的  - 啊, 明白了
I... I don't suppose you have any authority
我...我觉得你们没有得到授权
to search the building, have you?
能够搜查这栋大楼, 有吗？
No, Vaughn's too powerful,
he's got too many top people on his side.
不, Vaughn 很有手段．在高层里面有太多人站在他这边
You see, Doctor, I daren't make a move against him
unless I have good reason to do so.
你看, 博士, 我不敢对他有任何动作, 除非我有很好的理由
Well, it looks to me,
if Jamie and I want to find the Professor,
哦, 在我看来, 如果 Jamie 和我想要去找教授
we'll have to do it in our own way.
我们就只能用自己的方法
That's about the sum of it.
总体来说就是这样
However, should you find yourself
in any difficulty...
但是, 如果你们遇到任何困难...
Sergeant Walters!
Walters 中士
- Yes, sir?  - Got a TM-45 handy?
- 是, 长官？  - 手上有 TM-45?
Yes, sir. Right here.
有, 长官, 就在这里
- Is that a tank?  - Oh, no, no.
- 那是一架塔克吗？  - 噢, 不, 不是
My units are on constant alert,
我的部队会保持警惕
so should you find yourselves in any trouble,
所以如果你们发现自己遇到任何麻烦
- you can just give us a call.
- Jolly good!
- 就可以呼叫我们  - 太好了
- Here you are, sir.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
- 给你, 长官  - 谢谢你, 中士
Now, this is a small transceiver,
看, 这是一个小型收发器
range of about fifty miles on a set frequency.
在预定频率上有效范围大概是50英里
Just press this button and ask for me.
只要按这个钮就可以找我就可以了
Oh, yes, that's splendid! Yes.
This should come in very handy.
噢, 好, 这太棒了！是的，这应该非常方便
Call me anytime. I'm usually available.
随时呼我, 我一般都在
No. They must have gone out.
不, 他们肯定已经走了
Zoe?
Zoe?﻿
Isobel?
Isobel?﻿
Probably gone for a walk.
可能出去散步了
Look, Jamie, sandwiches. I'm hungry.
看, Jamie, 三明治．我饿了
- Want one?  - Thank you.
- 来一个吗？  - 谢谢你
You know, Doctor, that chap Mr Vaughn
doesn't seem such a bad man.
知道吗, 博士, Vaughn 那个家伙看着并不像是个坏人
(TURNS RADIO ON)
Oh, Jamie!
噢, Jamie!
How can I think when you've got that thing on?
你把这玩意儿打开我还怎么思考？
Hey!
嘿！
All right, all right.
好吧, 好吧
- Don't break it.  - All right!
- 别弄坏了  - 没事的！
I just want to have a look at it, that's all.
我只是想看一眼这东西, 仅此而已
Oh, yes.
噢, 对了
- It's an interesting little piece...
- What?
- 这是个有意思的小东西...  - 什么？
Well, well, well.
好, 好, 好
What have we here?
看看我们这有什么？
What do you mean, ''What have we here?''
你什么意思, ＂看看我们这里有什么＂
There's a micromonolithic circuit
in the back plate of this radio.
在这个收音机的后面板上有一个微型单晶片电路
Well, what's that?
哦, 那是什么？
It's a very complex circuit in miniature.
是一种非常复杂的电路, 做得很小
What's so odd about that, then?
那又有什么奇怪的？
It has nothing to do with the radio,
as far as I can see.
就我的观察, 它跟收音机功能无关
- Oh, Doctor, just put it back together again!
- All right.
- 噢, 博士, 还是把它放回去吧！  - 好吧
I don't suppose Zoe would have
left a note, do you?
我觉得 Zoe 不会留一张字条, 你说呢？
No, I can't see anything.
Well, you might at least help me look for it.
我也什么都没看见．是了, 你至少可以帮我找一下
I suggest we try the wall.
我建议我们看看墙上
Eh?
嗯？
Isobel never writes anything on paper.
Isobel 从不把东西写在纸上
- You can't lose a wall, remember?
- Oh.
- ＂你总不会弄丢一堵墙＂, 记得吗？  - 哦
Ah! ''Tired of waiting.
啊！ ＂等得不耐烦了
''Gone to IE offices to look for you.
Zoe and Isobel.''
＂出发去 IE 的办公室找你们．Zoe 和 Isobel＂
Jamie! We better go after them.
Jamie! 我们最好去找她们